Hello.
In this next lecture, we're going to go over how to create a game over screen.
So if our player character runs out of lights and they die, then we'll tell the player they got game
over.
But before we do that, we need to fix one thing.
So I updated my player character so they have one heart and one life.
And if they get hit and die and are on zero lives when they respawn, they'll just respawn in their
death animation.
So we need to fix this if we go over to our player's animation blueprint.
And go over to the bit where we transition from our player's death to the idle slash run animation.
Head inside here.
We made it so that if our player character has more than zero lives will transition them back from their
death to that idle such running animation.
The problem that is happening is my player character is respawning and they have zero lives.
And because it's not greater than zero.
They don't transition back into that idle run animation.
So in order to fix this, we're going to make a new system.
If we go to the player blueprint, create a new variable, and just call this respawn question mark.
When we respond, I'll play a character.
We're going to set this Boolean to be true.
So connect us node and make sure this is checked.
And if when we try to up back after they don't have more than zero lives, then we're going to set this
variable to be false and just connect this into here.
Then if we go into our characters animation blueprint and head inside here, just delete this life's
bit and instead just drag off here and get respawn.
And if this variable is true, then we'll make sure our character can transition from their death to
their idols that run animation.
So if I could compile and play.
Okay, so it looks like they failed to compile.
If we go to our plan blueprint, make sure to compile and then compile again.
And that should fix that.
Okay.
If we could play and my player character dies and is on zero lives, they should respawn with their
normal animations and everything working.
Okay, so the next thing we're going to do is make it so that if our player character dies when they're
on zero lives, they'll get game over.
If we close this and go over to our Widget Blueprint folder and right click and Go user Interface widget
Blueprint and just call this our game over widget.
If we open it up.
And in the palette, look for a canvas panel and just drag this in.
Then look for an image and just drag this into the canvas panel and make sure to anchor this across
the whole of our screen.
Under offset, I'm going to put zero in each of the values.
And I'm going to make the tint of this black and the alpha of this around 0.7.
Then if I look for some text.
And I'm going to drag this to the top center and also anchor it there.
And I'm going to make this text taxi game over.
And let's meet the size of this 100.
Then we look for a button.
And drag this into the center of the screen.
And also anchor it there.
We can look for some text and just track this text into the button and we'll make this button say,
retry.
And I'll just make this a bit bigger.
So something like 50.
And when we click on this button, so we select it, scroll down and go on clicked.
We are going to open level by name.
And I am going to open the main menu map.
So from that, my character can choose to play the level again or quit the game.
We can compile this and we want to go to a bank construct.
So when we show our game over screen, we want to show our mouse cursor.
That way the player character can click on this button.
So I'm going to right click and not forget player controller drag up here and it will set show mouse
cursor and make sure that I just leave this checked.
Then we'll just drive off here and look for set input mode.
UI.
Only that way our controller will be compatible with our menu.
And if we go back to the designer just to make this a bit more polished, we can add an animation when
we make this widget appear.
So if we go over to the animation tab, select, create new animation and call this game over animation.
Then if you select the canvas panel and go to animations and go track and just that the canvas panel,
because the canvas panel will include all of these elements, go track and select, render opacity.
Then under this value, put zero.
And click this little add new key.
So 0 seconds on our animation, we're going to make a whole widget invisible.
Then around one second we're going to make the render opacity one and just click add new key.
Over the course of one second, we're going to display our game over widget in order to make this animation
work and appear when we show this widget, head back to the graph.
And a bank construct.
After we do all of this, we will drag in our game over animation and just drag up here and look for
play animation.
And just connect this into here and this will automatically play our animation.
Now, if I just compile this and go over to my player blueprint.
If we respond.
An actor does not have more than zero lives, then we will just drag off here and look for quick widget.
Which it will create is going to be game over widget.
And then we will add this to our viewport.
I can then go compile and play.
And if I die now.
When I die and I'm out of life's, I get game over.
Then I'll say retry.
If I click this, it will take me to my main menu where I can then go, start and select all of my levels.